Register of the David Starr Jordan Papers, 1794-1950
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1872-1929
  - Titled works
    - Notes, notebooks (Box 48)
    - "Notes on Alsace-Lorraine," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "One Way to Outlaw War," Colliers, October 25, 1924(?) 1 printed copy (Folder 2)
    - Open Letter to the President, An, n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 3)
    - "Our Bugle-Call in France," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 4)
    - "Our Duty in Mexico," n.d. 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 typewritten) (Folder 5)
    - "Our Duty Towards Atrocities," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 6)
    - "Our Next Line of Action," August 5, 1915. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 7)
    - "Outlawry of War, The," Unity, April 13, 1922. 4 copies (2 printed, 2 carbons) (Folder 8)
    - "Outlawry of War, The," August, 1927. 7 copies (5 printed, 1 draft, 1 carbon) (Folder 9)
    - "Outline of the General Plan," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 10)
    - "Outlook for Peace, The," n.d. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 draft) (Folder 11)
    - "Pacific Ocean to Be the Theatre of Future World Politics," New York Journal and American, December 29, 1901. 1 printed copy (Folder 12)
    - "Pacificism and Law," n.d. 2 copies (1 draft, 1 carbon) (Folder 13)
    - "Pacifist, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 14)
    - "Pacifist in War-Time, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 15)
    - "Pact of the Rose Garden of Konopischt," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 2 carbon) (Folder 16)
    - "Palestine Regained," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 17)
    - "Pangermanism," appendix B, n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 18)
    - "Pangermanist Dream of Empire, The," n.d. 2 drafts (Folder 19)
    - "Passing of Don Luis, The," 1916. 5 copies (2 printed, 1 carbon, 2 drafts) (Folder 20)
    - "Patriotism," October, 1914. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 21)
    - "Peace," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 22)
    - "Peace and the College," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 23)
    - "Peace Movement in Holland, The," n.d. 3 copies (1 handwritten, 2 carbons) (Folder 24)
    - "Peace Pilgrimage, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 25)
    - Peace Plan. "Brains vs. Bullets--Love vs. Hate," n.d. 6 printed copies (Folder 26)
    - "Peace System, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 27)
    - "Peace To Be the Topic of Toronto Meet," San Francisco Chronicle, May 29, 1927. 4 printed copies (Folder 28)
    - "Peace Workers Through the Ages, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 29)
    - "People and Foreign Policy, The," March 21, 22, 1926. 3 copies (2 printed, 1 carbon) (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "People and the War Castes, The," The Stanford Sequoia, December, 1917. 1 printed copy (Folder 2)
    - "Permanent Peace," n.d., 1 draft (Folder 3)
    - "Physical Decadence," August 11, 1915. 1 printed copy (Folder 4)
    - "Pity the Poor Hermit: How Korea Is Affected by the Conflict Between Japanese Science and Japanese Militarism," Sunset, January, 1920. 1 printed copy (Folder 5)
    - "Plain American and the League of Nations, The," n.d. 2 typewritten copies (Folder 6)
    - "Plan By Which the United States May Cooperate with Other Nations in Securing World Peace, A," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 7)
    - "Plan of a World Center, The," 1913. 1 draft (Folder 8)
    - "Plan of Education for Peace, A," The Herald of Peace, April, 1928. 1 printed copy (Folder 9)
    - "Plan of Education for Peace and the Promotion of World Amity Including Stress on Possible Official Cooperation by World Governments," 1924. 3 copies (1 typewritten, 2 carbons) (Folder 10)
    - "Plan of Education to Develop International Justice and Friendship, A," 1925. 14 printed copies (Folder 11)
    - "Plea for Clarification of the Issues," March 23, 1917. 1 draft (Folder 12)
    - Poetry. 1910, 1925. 1 mimeographed booklet. 1 printed poem (Folder 13)
    - "Political Outlook, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 14)
    - "Preparedness for Peace," February 12, 1915. 3 copies (1 printed, 2 carbons) (Folder 15)
    - "Preparedness if Need Be," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 typewritten) (Folder 16)
    - "Problem of the War Traders, The," n.d. 5 copies (1 typewritten, 4 carbons) (Folder 17)
    - "Problems of the Peace Table"
      - II. The Economic Situation, Sunset, February, 1919. 2 printed copies (Folder 18)
      - III. The Heritage of Debt, Sunset, March, 1919. 3 printed copies (Folder 19)
      - IV. The Freedom of the Seas, Sunset, April, 1919. 2 printed copies (Folder 20)
      - V. Self-Determination for Ireland, Sunset, May, 1919. 1 printed copy (Folder 21)
      - VI. Japan and the Society of Nations, Sunset, June, 1919. 3 printed copies (Folder 22)
      - VII. The Right of Conquest and the League of Nations, Sunset, July, 1919. 5 printed copies (3 complete, 2 incomplete) (Folder 23)
      - VIII. The League of Nations and the Treaty of Peace, Sunset, August, 1919. 1 printed copy (Folder 24)
    - "Prospects of Universal Peace," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 25)
    - "Public Opinion and Public Will," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 26)
    - "Queries," Life, n.d. 1 printed copy (Folder 27)
    - "Question of Alsace-Lorraine, The," Everyman, February 27, 1914. 1 printed copy (Folder 28)
    - "Quiet in the Balkans," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 draft) (Folder 29)
    - "Rassenfortschritt und Krieg," 1924, Die neue Generation. 1 printed copy (Folder 30)
    - "Reign of Hate in Macedonia, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 31)
    - "Relations of Japan and the United States," reprint from The Journal of Race Development, January, 1912. 1 printed copy (Folder 32)
    - "Renaissance of Civilization, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 33)
    - "Report of David Starr Jordan," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 34)
    - "Republic of China, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 35)
    - "Results of Arbitration," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 36)
    - "Reversed Selection Due to War," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 37)
    - Review of:
      - Cerf, Barry, Alsace-Lorraine Since 1870, n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 38)
      - Collins, Frederick L., This King Business, n.d. 3 printed copies (Folder 39)
      - Eddy, Sherwood and Kirby Page, The Case Against War, and Questions and Answers Concerning War, n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 40)
      - Fisher, Galen, Creative Force in Japan, n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 41)
      - Fisher, Irving, League or War, n.d. 3 printed copies (Folder 42)
      - Folks, Homer, The Human Costs of the War, Nation, October 13, 1920. 2 carbon copies (Folder 43)
      - Guérard, Albert Léon, Reflections on the Napoleanic Legend, n.d. 3 printed copies (Folder 44)
      - Herron, George Davis, The Defeat in the Victory, 1925. 1 printed copy (Folder 45)
      - House, Colonel Edward Mondell, The Intimate Papers of Colonel House, Argonaut, April 8, 1926. 1 printed copy (Folder 46)
      - Hunter, Allan A., Youth's Adventure, Argonaut, February 26, 1926. 1 printed copy (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - Irwin, Will, Christ or Mars, December 17, 1923. 3 printed copies (Folder 2)
      - Kagawa, Toyohiko, Across the Death Line, School and Society, November 24, 1923. 2 printed copies (Folder 3)
      - Kellor, Frances, Security Against War, n.d. 2 carbon copies (Folder 4)
      - Lodge, Henry Cabot, The Senate and the League of Nations, Argonaut, January 16, 1926. 1 printed copy (Folder 5)
      - Pollock, Channing, The Enemy, Argonaut, November 7, 1925. 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 printed) (Folder 6)
      - Putnam, Ruth, Luxemburg and Her Neighbors, Survey, February 15, 1919. 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 draft) (Folder 7)
      - Satomi, Kishio, Discovery of Japanese Idealism, Argonaut, November 14, 1925. 3 printed copies (Folder 8)
      - Shaw, Frederick John, Anglo-American Relations, 1861-1865, by Brougham Villiers (pseudonym), Argonaut, January 30, 1926. 2 copies (1 printed, 1 carbon) (Folder 9)
      - Shaw, Frederick John, "The Bankruptcy of the Belligerents," War and Peace, July, 1918. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 10)
      - Sterling, Ada, The Jew and Civilization, n.d. 2 printed copies (Folder 11)
      - Villard, Fanny Garrison, William Lloyd Garrison on Non-Resistance, n.d. 2 carbon copies (Folder 12)
      - Wright, Henry Wilkes, The Moral Standards of Democracy, Argonaut, September 12, 1925. 3 printed copies (Folder 13)
    - "Revival of Europe, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 14)
    - "Right of Conquest, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 15)
    - "Rise of Preparedness, The," 1914. 2 carbon copies (Folder 16)
    - "Roosevelt As I Knew Him," January 8, 1919. 1 printed copy (Folder 17)
    - "Roosevelt's Birds," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 18)
    - "Root of the Evil, The," 1918. 5 printed copies (Folder 19)
    - "Rupes Tres," The Cornell Era, September 29, 1871. 1 printed copy (Folder 20)
    - "Ruskin and the Glory of War," n.d. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 21)
    - "Sacramento Japanese," n.d. 1 partial copy, typewritten (Folder 22)
    - "Salt of Death, The," a compilation bearing on war, made in 1910 but not published. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 23)
    - "San Francisco Japanese Schools," n.d. 1 partial copy, typewritten (Folder 24)
    - "Sanctions for War, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 25)
    - "Scholar and Internationalism, The," Phi Beta Kappa Address, University of California, May 10, 1915. 1 handwritten copy (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - "Science and Sciosophy," proceedings of the California Academy of Social Sciences, December 19-20, 1924. 1 printed copy (Folder 2)
    - "Science - War - Religion," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 3)
    - "Search for the Guilty Nation, The," n.d. 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 typewritten) (Folder 4)
    - "Search for the Superman, The," n.d. 2 handwritten copies (Folder 5)
    - "Second to None," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 6)
    - "Self-Determination for Ireland," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 7)
    - "Senate and the League, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 8)
    - "Seven Billion Dollar Loan, The," n.d. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 draft) (Folder 9)
    - "Shall We Arm?" October, 1914. 3 copies (1 typewritten, 2 handwritten) (Folder 10)
    - "Sharks Teeth From California," reprint from The American Journal of Science, May, 1922. 1 printed copy (Folder 11)
    - "Silas Marner," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 12)
    - "Skilled Laborer and War, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 13)
    - "Slowing Down of Trade, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 14)
    - "Social Darwinism and the War System," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 15)
    - "Sofia," n.d. 2 carbon copies (Folder 16)
    - "Sole Condition of Permanent Peace, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 17)
    - "Some Aspects of War - Philosophy," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 18)
    - "Some Hebrew Pacifists," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 19)
    - "Some Lessons of the War," n.d. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 printed) (Folder 20)
    - "Some Phases of the Aftermath," Sunset, n.d. 1 printed copy (Folder 21)
    - "Some Recent Phases of the Peace Movement in Japan," November 18, 1921. 3 carbon copies (Folder 22)
    - "Spirit of Alsace-Lorraine, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 23)
    - "Spirit of Nationalism, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 24)
    - "Spirit of the Camp, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 25)
    - "Standing Incentives to War, The," Unpopular Review, January-June, 1914. 3 copies (1 carbon, 1 typewritten, 1 printed) (Folder 26)
    - "Story of the Civil War: Fifty Years After," 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 typewritten), 1 handwritten draft (Folder 27)
    - "Strength of Being Clean, The," speech given on the Forty Fifth Anniversary of the Young Men's Christian Associations, San Francisco, January 30, 1898. 1 printed copy (Folder 28)
    - "Strength of Germany, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - "Strikes and Wages," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 2)
    - "Submergence of Democracy, The," n.d. 5 copies (1 typewritten, 4 carbons) (Folder 3)
    - "Sunny Side of War, The," Unity, June 28, 1923. 1 printed copy, 1 draft (Folder 4)
    - "Sussex Note, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 5)
    - "Syllabus of Lectures on International Conciliation," given at Stanford University by Jordan and Edward Benjamin Krehbiel, 1912. 2 printed copies (Folder 6)
    - "Taking a Dare," n.d. 3 carbon copies. (Folder 7)
    - "Teacher and War, The," 1915. 2 drafts (handwritten and printed) (Folder 8)
    - "Terms of Peace, The," n.d. 5 printed copies. Same title, different version, n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 9)
    - "Three Counts Against Tobacco," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 10)
    - "To Barbara with other Verses," 1897. 1 printed copy (Folder 11)
    - "To Lasting Peace," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 12)
    - "To Our Colleagues in Europe," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 13)
    - "To Scholars, Writers and Artists of Great Britain and Germany," 1914. 3 carbon copies (Folder 14)
    - "Toward Democratic Peace," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 15)
    - "Trade of Neutrals and Belligerents, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 16)
    - "Trail of War in Macedonia, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 17)
    - "Trail of War in Macedonia, The", The American Museum Journal, October, 1915. 1 printed copy (Folder 18)
    - Translated by David Starr Jordan. Alfred Nippold, "Parlons franchement de l'Alsace-Lorraine," n.d. 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 19)
    - "Treaty of London, The," 1913. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 20)
    - "Trend Toward Peace," n.d. 7 printed copies (Folder 21)
    - "Truth Basis of Highest Patriotism," July 1, 1926. 2 printed copies (Folder 22)
    - "Two Germanys, The," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 23)
    - "Two Germanys in Mexico, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 24)
    - "Two-Party System, The," January 24, 1926. 3 printed copies (Folder 25)
    - "Tyranny of the Frontier," n.d. 3 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon, 1 handwritten) (Folder 26)
    - "Unarmed and Unafraid," n.d. 1 printed copy. (Folder 27)
    - "Uncle Sam's Solar Plexus," April 10, 1915. 1 printed copy (Folder 28)
    - "University Conferences on War, Peace and International Polity," August, 1915. 1 draft (Folder 29)
    - "Unseen Empire, The," speech in Honolulu, August 15, 1911. 3 printed copies (Folder 30)
    - "Value of Internationalism, The," n.d. 2 carbon copies (Folder 31)
    - "Victory," an open letter to Congress, June, 1917. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 32)
    - "Victory Message, A," n.d. 1 draft, 1 handwritten copy (Folder 33)
    - "Victory of Peace, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy. (Folder 34)
    - "War," n.d. 1 handwritten draft (Folder 35)
    - "War, and Argument Against Peace," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 36)
    - "War and Its Aftermath," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 37)
    - "War and Manhood," n.d. 1 printed copy (Folder 38)
    - "War and Manhood," reprint from the Proceedings of the National Education Association, Boston, Massachusetts, July, 1910. 3 printed copies (Folder 39)
    - "War and Peace," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 40)
    - "War and Superstition," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 41)
    - "War and the Ballott-Box," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 42)
    - "War and the Breed," 1915. 7 printed copies of advertisements for book by Jordan. Carbon and handwritten copy of bibliography (Folder 43)
    - "War and the Crime Wave," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 44)
    - "War and the League of Nations," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - "War and the State," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 2)
    - "War and the Supreme Evil," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 3)
    - "War and Waste," Peace, September, 1912. 1 printed copy (Folder 4)
    - "War and History in the Making," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 5)
    - "War Making and Its Remedy," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 6)
    - "War Marriages," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 7)
    - "War Not Inevitable," n.d. 2 drafts (Folder 8)
    - "War Scares and War Armaments," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 9)
    - "War-Spiders, The," 1916. 2 carbon copies (Folder 10)
    - "War System, The," n.d. 2 versions with the same title, 1 handwritten, 1 carbon (Folder 11)
    - "War System and Militarism, The," n.d. (Folder 12)
    - "Warfare," n.d. 1 draft (Folder 13)
    - "War's Aftermath," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 14)
    - "War's Aftermath in Paraguay," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 15)
    - "Way Out of War, A," n.d. 2 copies (1 typewritten, 1 carbon) (Folder 16)
    - "Way to Peace, A," n.d. 3 copies (1 typewritten, 2 carbons) (Folder 17)
    - "Ways of Pangermany, The," reprint from The Scientific Monthly, January, 1917. 4 copies (1 typewritten, 3 printed). Incomplete manuscript prepared in 1916 with same title (Folder 18)
    - "Ways to Lasting Peace," n.d. 1 draft (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - "Ways to World Peace," Parts I and II, n.d. 2 copies (1 carbon, 1 printed) (Folder 2)
    - "What Can Germany Pay?" n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 3)
    - "What Germany Has Paid," n.d. 3 printed copies (Folder 4)
    - "What of Democracy?" with other war-time addresses and studies, n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 5)
    - "What of Mexico?" n.d. 2 copies (1 printed, 1 carbon), 1 partial copy (Folder 6)
    - "What of the Nation?"
      - "The Safeguard for Peace--Mr. Ford's Peace Pilgrimage," Sunset, February, 1916. 3 copies (1 carbon, 2 printed) (Folder 7)
      - "Our Fight Against Democracy--The Panhandle of Alaska," Sunset, March, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 8)
      - "Preparedness If Need Be--Strikes and Wages--An International Loss," Sunset, April, 1916. 2 printed copies (Folder 9)
      - "The Military Expert on International Affairs--The Spirit of the Camp," Sunset, May, 1916. 3 printed copies (Folder 10)
      - "The Moral Damage of War," July, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 11)
      - "Intervention in Mexico--An Argument for War," Sunset, August, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 12)
      - "Pacifism and the Presidency--The Mexican Revolution--Salvage," Sunset, September, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 13)
      - "England's Preparedness--Compulsory Service in New Zealand--The Control of Credit," Sunset, October, 1916. 2 printed copies (Folder 14)
      - "For the National Honor," Sunset, November, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 15)
      - "The Charge Against Democracy--Victory and Defeat--The Soulless War," Sunset, December, 1916. 1 printed copy (Folder 16)
      - "The President's Note--The Balkan Brew," Sunset, March, 1917. 1 printed copy (Folder 17)
      - "The High Cost of Living," Sunset, April, 1917. 1 printed copy (Folder 18)
    - "What Peace Workers Believe," n.d. 3 copies (1 carbon, 2 typewritten and handwritten drafts) (Folder 19)
    - "What Shall We Say?" 1912-[1916]. Drafts, excerpts, printed galleys, printed copies. "These were reprinted from communications to various journals, and were sent to people interested in the prevention of war, without copyright restrictions. Numbers 1-5 first appeared in Unity, and without numbering in the Atlantic Monthly. They were copied widely by newspapers, also appearing in many journals, sometimes without numbers" (p. 47, David Starr Jordan: A Bibliography of His Writings, 1871-1931, Compiled by Alice N. Hays, Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, 1952) (Folder 20-21)
    - "What the Church Can Do for Peace," n.d. 2 carbon copies (Folder 22)
    - "What We Owe to Saint Routine," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 23)
    - "What Were America's War Gains," n.d. 2 printed copies (Folder 24)
    - "When East Meets East: Japan's Conquest and China's Resentment Create Bad Blood in the Orient," Sunset, December, 1919. 2 printed copies (Folder 25)
    - "Where Uncle Sam's Solar Plexus Is Located," April 17, 1915. 1 printed copy (Folder 26)
    - "Where Is the Civilist?" August 24, 1914. 3 copies (2 carbons, 1 draft) (Folder 27)
    - "Woman Workers for Peace," Out West, January, 1916. 1 carbon copy (Folder 28)
    - "World Is Very Slow to Learn, The," n.d. 1 handwritten copy (Folder 29)
    - "World Union of Peace, The," n.d. 1 typewritten copy (Folder 30)
    - "World's Great Men Branded Infidels by Mob," n.d. 3 printed copies (Folder 31)
    - "World's Helpers, The," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 32)
    - "Wurzel des Uebels, Die," 1918. 2 printed copies (Folder 33)
    - "Youth's Adventure," n.d. 1 carbon copy (Folder 34)
  - Untitled works, by subject
    - Alsace-Lorraine (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Australia (Folder 2)
    - Balkans (Folder 3)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 4)
    - Christian Science Monitor - Editorial proofs (Folder 5)
    - Conscientious objectors (Folder 6)
    - Debt (Folder 7)
    - Democracy (Folder 8)
    - Disarmament (Folder 9)
    - Economics (Folder 10)
    - European War, 1914-1918
      - General (Folder 11)
      - American entry (Folder 12)
      - Atrocities (Folder 13)
    - Far East (Folder 14)
    - France (Folder 15)
    - Germany (Folder 16)
    - Great Britain (Folder 17)
    - Hoover, Herbert C. (Folder 18)
    - Hungary (Folder 19)
    - Japan (Folder 20)
    - Japanese immigration (Folder 21)
    - Kimber, Clifford (Folder 22)
    - Lane, Ralph (Folder 23)
    - League of Nations (Folder 24)
    - Liberals (Folder 25)
    - Mexico (Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous - Speech notes, drafts, incomplete drafts, parts of articles, etc. (Folder 27-30)
    - Miscellaneous - Speech notes, drafts, incomplete drafts, parts of articles, etc. (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - Netherlands (Folder 4)
    - Pacifism (Folder 5)
    - Pan-Pacific Union (Folder 6)
    - Pangermanism (Folder 7)
    - Patriotism (Folder 8)
    - Peace (Folder 9)
    - Philippines (Folder 10)
    - Politics (Folder 11)
    - Presidential Campaign, 1920 (Folder 12)
    - Religion (Folder 13)
    - Stanford, Leland, Mrs. (Folder 14)
    - United States
      - General (Folder 15)
      - Army (Folder 16)
      - Congress (Folder 17)
      - Navy (Folder 18)
    - Veterans (Folder 19)
    - War (Folder 20)
    - Wilson, Woodrow (Folder 21)
    - World organizations (Folder 21)
- JESSIE KNIGHT JORDAN FILE, 1883-1950
  - Correspondence, 1883-1950
    - General
      - Undated (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - 1889 (Folder 2)
      - 1892 (Folder 3)
      - 1893 (Folder 4)
      - 1920 (Folder 5)
      - 1922 (Folder 6)
      - 1923 (Folder 7)
      - 1924 (Folder 8)
      - 1926 (Folder 9)
      - 1928 (Folder 10)
      - 1929 (Folder 11)
      - 1930-1931 (Folder 12)
      - 1932 (Folder 13)
      - 1933 (Folder 14)
      - 1934 (Folder 15)
      - 1935-1936 (Folder 16)
      - 1937 (Folder 17)
      - 1938 (Folder 18)
      - 1939 (Folder 19)
      - 1940 (Folder 20)
      - 1941 (Box 86, Folder 1-12)
      - 1942 (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 4)
      - 1945 (Folder 5)
      - 1947 (Folder 6)
      - 1948 (Folder 7)
      - 1949 (Folder 8)
      - 1950 (Folder 9)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck and Eleanor, 1941-1947 (Folder 10)
    - Hoover, Lou Henry, 1927-1940 (Folder 11)
    - Knight, Austin (brother of Jessie Knight Jordan), 1883-1926 (Folder 12-15)
    - National Council for the Prevention of War, 1935-1938 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - People's Mandate Committee, 1946-1947 (Folder 2)
    - Terman, Lewis M., n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1911-1922
    - Titled
      - "Concerning Barbara's Sickness and Death," n.d., 1 handwritten copy (Folder 4)
      - "Jane Lathrop Stanford, 1828-1905," n.d., 1 carbon copy (Folder 5)
    - Untitled
      - Accounts of trips to Japan, 1911, 1922, handwritten, typewritten, notes, drafts (Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous notes (Folder 7)
      - Tribute to Vernon Kellogg, n.d., 1 handwritten draft (Folder 8)
  - Subject File, 1930-1949
    - Miscellany (Folder 9)
    - Printed material
      - Clippings (Folder 10)
      - Newsletters (Folder 11)
      - Pamphlets (Folder 12)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1894-1947
  - Addams, Jane (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Agassiz Association (Folder 2)
  - Agriculture (Folder 3)
  - Alsace-Lorraine (Folder 4)
  - American Association for International Conciliation (Folder 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Folder 6)
  - American Defense Society (Folder 7)
  - American Free Trade League (Folder 8)